# MOHAMED ALMAHDY

### **Mobile Applications Developer**

- @ engmohamedalmahdy@gmail.com
- **+201096475710**
- Nasr City, Cairo
- LightFeather42

- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/eng-mohamed-almahdy
- https://github.com/eng-mohamedalmahdy

#### **PROFILE**

**Mid-level** Mobile Apps Engineer with **2+ years** of hands-on experience in Kotlin, Java, and Swift. Successfully developed and delivered **10+ mobile apps** across Native Android, iOS, and Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) in **3+ companies**. Possess solid knowledge in digital marketing, enhancing overall versatility.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Mid Level Android developer | DTag

# 04/2023 - Present

- Created & Contributed at 3 Mobile Apps:
  - Whizzy.
  - Samoolah For User & Agent.

### JR. Software developer | Virtual Worker Now

**12/2021 - 5/2022** 

- 2 Websites contributions & 2 Mobile Apps contributions
  - Pet Materices
  - Virtual Worker Now
  - Virtual Courses Now

#### JR. Android developer | ElMnassa Innovation

**i** 6/2020 - 12/2020

• 2 Mobile Apps contributions

### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

 $\left( \mathsf{Kotlin} \right) \left( \mathsf{Java} \right) \left( \mathsf{Swift} \right)$ 

### **FRAMEWORKS**

Native Android Kotlin Multiplatform

Native iOS

### **ANDROID TOOLS**

Kotlin Compose | Coroutines | Retrofit

Rx Java & Kotlin Image Loaders

Koin Room Realm Dagger hilt

JUnit MocKK Mockito

#### **IOS TOOLS**

Ulkit Storyboard Auto layout

Swift UI) GCD RX Swift & Cocoa

Core Data Alamofire Kingfisher

#### **SKILLS**

- Strong grasp of **OOP**, data structures, and algorithms.
- Proficient in applying architecture patterns such as MVVM.
- Good understanding of design patterns & SOLID principles.
- Solid understanding of HTTP Requests and RESTful APIs.
- Experienced in creating and executing thorough Unit testing.
- Skilled in multithreading, & libraries like Coroutines & GCD.
- Proficient in applying Dependency Injection principle.
- Experience in other programming paradigms such as **Fp** & **Rx**.
- Expertise in version control systems such as Git and GitHub.
- Proficient in Gradle buildSrc & Plugins and catalog versions.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.S Computer Engineering | Al-Azhar University.

**i** 2017 - 2021

• Graduation Project: Zakerly ( E-learning Mobile App ) Grade : Excellent

### **RECENT BOOKS READINGS**

- Clean Mobile Arch.
- Algorithms Unplugged
- Gradle for Android

- Clean Arch.
- Head First OOA/D
- My book list: HERE

### Android Projects

### Samoolah 🔒 📥

- Services Provider App With 2 Distributions 1 For the Client 1 For the Technician
- Used Technologies : MVVM with Modularization Compose Rest APIs with Retrofit Navigation Component Kotlin Coroutines with Flows

### Islami 180 | > 📥

- Islamic application contains: Quran + Quran Tafseer Prayer Azan Qibla Finder Azkar Hijri Calendar Tasbeeh
- Used Technologies: MVVM Room database (for Quarn data storage) Retrofit (for prayer azan API requests) Android navigation component Json to Gson serialization Work Manager Notifications Manager Alarm Manager Senesor Manager And more

### Zakerly 😱 📥

- Zakerly is an app used to connect students with teachers to learn online as an E-learning service And helps them attending online sessions individuals or groups
- Used Technologies: MVVM Firebase Kit (real time database & cloud messaging) Realm database (for data storage)
   Retrofit (for FCM API requests) Android navigation component Json to Gson serialization Jitsi meet sdk

### **iOS** Projects

### Whizzy 🕳

- **Description**: Whizzy is a revolutionary mobile application designed to simplify the process of renting electric cars for short rides. With its user-friendly interface and advanced features, Whizzy aims to provide a modern and convenient solution for urban commuters looking for eco-friendly transportation options.
- **Used Technologies**: MVVM architecture with Swift UI, Alamofire for networking, Kingfisher for image loading, Combine GCD for asynchronous programming.

### 

- Pet Matrices is a lifestyle application for your pets where you can record and track your pets activities and given calories, you also can record and track their health condition and get some nice advice from an expert
- Used Technologies: SwiftUI, REST API, MVVM archticture pattern, Swift GCD

### Memorise 🕠 🐞

Memorising game created with swift and Swift UI.
 A project for Stanford CS193p course at: https://cs193p.sites.stanford.edu/

### **■ Kotlin Multiplatform Projects**

#### Masarify **■**

- Innovative expenses tracker App
- leveraging Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) for seamless development across multiple platforms. Demonstrated proficiency in KMP, delivering a feature-rich application with multi-account support, dynamic categories, and multi-currency.
- Used Technologies: MVVM -CMP- SQLDelight KTor Voyager Router KotlinX Serialization KAMEL

#### Ion K

- Residential compound community app that also shows the developer other compounds and projects.
- Online-based, leveraging Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) for seamless development across multiple platforms.
- Used Technologies: MVI CMP KTor Voyager KotlinX Serialization KAMEL

## More Projects at my GitHub O